so I have been watching the man in the
high castle and got introduced to this
Nazi concept called a useless eater
which the definition is a people people
people with a serious medical problem or
disability seen as requiring help from
society but giving nothing back so of
course the Nazis just murdered everyone
who they thought to be disabled and what
they considered a useless eater
in my opinion there are useless eaters
on this planet and they are in no way
the disabled they are in no way the
people who did not cease thought of as
useless eaters they are the people whose
only contribution on this planet is the
money they have because money in the
hands of somebody else would be just the
same so if you're not giving a gift
beyond into the money that you have you
kind of are useless leader you're giving
and yet I still don't think you should
of course be annihilated
I think that
finding ways for people to contribute
their passion I think those people who
are just there money are some of the
most unhappy people because they get it
they get that's all they are
they don't have their I mean some of
them also have their brain working for
them that's why they're able to make the
money but a lot of them don't they just
happen to be lucky they just happened to
have inherited a their a trust-fund kid
and so they only have money money to
spend so their day spent shopping
they're just a consumer just a Money
holder and I think we project onto
society a lot of our own inner wounds
and so I think that's where a lot of
ableism comes from is that we see
someone we think of as less than and if
they're less than us we like put all of
our insecurities on them because if we
are not worthy as we are they better not
be worthy as they are when the truth is
everyone in society everyone that exists
on this planet is worthy equally worthy
of love of health of everything and by
health I mean health care we're not
clearly clearly health or we'd have
equal help but what we have to give on
this planet is often comes from a place
of disadvantage I know from my
experience that my disabilities the
things that society looks at as I'm now
inferior because I can't work full-time
I can't even work part-time but from
that space that is often the critique I
get for this global cooperative idea
like what about lazy people who just
want to sit around on the couch watch
television like that's literally what I
was and came up with the idea on how we
saved the entire planet
you cannot say what someone else is and
isn't contributing by looking at them
you can't tell what they have to give
and often those of us who have struggled
the most physically mentally emotionally
have the most to give not in society
where being successful in contributing
has a very specific box you have to fit
into but when were able to ask what can
I contribute from where I am Who am I
why am I here
a whole new world opens up like we were
able to contribute on a whole new level
and so this new leap forward this
disability union or whatever if the baby
is still coming we are gonna create a
world that works for us we are gonna
create the resources we need to
collaborate and share our mental
capacity our physical capacity our
financial capacity our time our energy
with each other so there doesn't need to
be anybody from the outside helping us
and the neuro-diverse the physically
diverse the emotionally diverse are
going to create the tools that saves all
of humanity and
although some people with disabilities
of course can work full and part-time
with accommodation there's also tons of
us who can't can't fit into that
capitalist system and
historically the answer has been to
annihilate us or we're still thought of
as useless in leaders in our capitalist
society it's like oh we have to I have
to give you a stand up desk I have to
make a wheelchair accessible washroom so
inconvenient
they don't look at everything they get
from the person who those accommodations
help because they're not getting a less
than employee they're getting someone
with experience that other people don't
have don't possess and you bring so much
to the table if only they are allowing
and so we are going to create that table
we're not going to demand the tables
that exist well we might demand the
tables it exists to be more accessible
to us but we can without doing that
create a space
where we accept each other
and I'm so excited by this next leap
just it's my new special interest so I
just wanted this today's lovely video is
on useless eaters that is going to be
somewhere in the title and it's not who
the Nazis thought they were
those of us who would have been murdered
under that regime have more to give not
less and it's just society doesn't value
what we have to give at the moment and
they're going to because what we have to
give it's going to save everybody on
this planet a better world is on its way
and it's gonna be brought to you about
inroad physically diverse please like
and subscribe I'll see you tomorrow and
back in Vancouver